My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل متحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case is the continuation of a reunion murder case!
قضية اليوم تتمة لجريمة قتل !مناسبة لمّ الشمل
Let's listen to "Mune ga Doki Doki" as we review the last episode!
"لنستمع لـ "موني وا دوكي دوكي !بينما نراجع الحلقة الماضية
The old man's college buddies had a reunion at the hot spring resort, "Benkei."
أتى العمّ لمناسبة لمّ شمل مع زملائه من الجامعة "في منتجع الينابيع الساخنة "بينكي
The attendees were the club manager, Horikoshi Yumi,
وكان الحاضرون مديرة النادي، هوريكوشي يومي
the model shop owner, Omura Jun,
ومالك متجر النماذج، أومورا جون
his wife, Ayashiro Noriko,
وزوجته أياشيرو نوريكو
and then me, Ran, and the old man.
وأخيرًا، أنا وران مع العمّ
We went to wake up Horikoshi Yumi,
ذهبنا لإيقاظ هوريكوشي يومي
who was still in her room after the fireworks show ended,
التي كانت لا تزال نائمة في غرفتها بعد نهاية عرض الألعاب النارية
only to find that she had committed suicide
ووجدناها ميتةً بعد إطلاقها النار
by shooting herself in the head!
على رأسها مُنتحرة
A makeshift autopsy showed that she had died seven hours earlier--
أظهرت نتائج التشريح السريع أنّها ماتت قبل 7 ساعات
at around 3:00 p.m., when everyone was playing ping-pong
عند الثالثة مساءً أثناء لعب الجميع لكرة الطاولة
before leaving for the fireworks show!
قبل المغادرة لعرض الألعاب النارية
Kogoro's Reunion Murder Case (Part 2).
جريمة قتل مناسبة لمّ شمل كوغورو (الجزء الثاني)
Come to think of it, she did say something...
...سبق أن قالت يومي
I really wish I were dead...
أتمنّى لو كنت ميتة حقاً
She must've been serious!
لا بدّ أنّها كانت تعاني
Say, how did Yumi-san shoot herself in the head?
كيف أطلقت يومي-سان النار على رأسها؟
What are you talking about, Conan-kun?!
ما الذي تقوله يا كونان-كن؟
Don't ask strange questions!
!لا تطرح أسئلة غريبة
How?!
!كيف؟
She put the gun up to her head like so and--
...صوّبت على رأسها هكذا و
Wait! Mori! What is it?!
!موري! ما الخطب؟! ماذا هناك؟
Mori!
!موري
Tell me, Nakamichi.
ناكاميتشي
Normally when someone commits suicide with a gun,
عندما ينتحر أحدهم بمسدّس عادةً
they stick the barrel against their head, right?
يلصق الفوهة برأسه، صحيح؟
Yes...
أجل
Then her bullet wound is missing something vital.
هناك أمرٌ ناقص في جرحها إذاً
You're right! Burn marks!
!معك حق! علامات الحرق
Yes.
أجل
When you shoot a gun,
عندما تطلق من مسدّس، سيصاحب الرصاصة تيّار هواء ساخن
If you shoot with the gun against your head,
إن أطلقت بالمسدّس بينما يلامس رأسك مباشرةً
it would have to leave burn marks behind!
ستبقى آثار احتراق بلا شك
The fact that there are none here means...
...لكن عدم وجود أيٍّ منها
...that someone else shot her?!
تقصد أنّ شخصاً آخر أطلق عليها؟
Yes.
أجل
Someone shot her and then tried to make it look like a suicide!
قتل أحدهم يومي وزيّف الأمر ليبدو انتحاراً
Someone in this inn...
...أحد في هذا النُزل
You don't think one of us did it, do you?!
لا تعتقدا أنّ أحداً بيننا فعلها، صحيح؟
Now, now. Don't get ahead of yourself.
لا تستبق الأحداث
I just said the murder took place at approximately 3:00.
قلنا أنّ الجريمة وقعت عند قرابة الثالثة مساءً
That was right after she went off on her own.
أي بعد تركها لنا مباشرةً
We were all in the ping-pong room from 3:00 to 6:00,
كنّا جميعاً في غرفة كرة الطاولة من الثالثة حتّى السادسة
so none of us could have done it.
فيستحيل أنّ أحدنا ارتكبها
The only time someone left
الوحيد الذي غادر
was when Omura went to the restroom.
كان أومورا عند ذهابه لدورة المياه
But that was well past 5:00,
لكن كان ذلك بعد الخامسة
and he came back in less than a minute.
كما عاد في أقلّ من دقيقة
He couldn't have done it either.
يستحيل أنّ أومورا ارتكبها أيضاً
So then it was an outside job?
كانت جريمةً خارجية إذاً؟
Yes, perhaps.
أجل، ربما
As you can see,
كما ترون
the killer could have gone anywhere along the roof,
كان بمقدرة القاتل الذهاب لأيّ مكان على السقف
plus the door wasn't locked.
كما أنّ الباب لم يكن مقفلاً
It's very conceivable that someone entered from outside.
من المحتمل جدّاً تسلل أحدهم من الخارج
At any rate, let's hear what the employees have to say.
لنستجوب موظّفي النُزل بأيّ حال
Someone might've seen a suspicious character.
ربما رأى أحدهم شخصاً مشبوهاً
Anybody suspicious?
شخص مشبوه؟
We were all out to lunch at three o'clock,
خرجنا جميعاً لتناول الغداء عند الثالثة
and even after we came back, there was no one that suspicious--
...ولم نجد شخصاً مشبوهاً لذاك الحد بعد عودتنا
Oh! Actually, there was such a person!
!لحظة، كان هناك واحد
What were they like?!
كيف كان؟
-A young lass with a child.
كانت شابةً مع صبيّ
She seemed very distraught and rushed straight upstairs!
بدت متوترةً جداً وهرعت للطابق العلوي
Can you describe this girl?!
أيمكنك وصف تلك الفتاة؟
Oh, she's right there behind you.
إنّها وراءكما
It was those two young'uns.
إنّها تلك الفتاة والصبيّ
I believe that was around 6:30, just when the fireworks started...
أظنّ ذلك كان عند السادسة والنصف مع بدء الألعاب النارية
She's talking about when we came to wake Yumi-san up
تقصد عندما ذهبنا لإيقاظ يومي-سان
so she wouldn't miss the fireworks!
كيلا تفوتها الألعاب النارية
Oh...
...حينذاك إذاً
We went to her room and were about to go in, but...
...ذهبنا لغرفتها وكنّا على وشك الدخول
...I stopped them.
لكنّي أوقفتهما
She gets grumpy when people wake her up,
مزاج يومي يتعكر عند استيقاظها
so I figured it best that they didn't.
لذا حذّرتهما من إيقاظها
Nakamichi? You were still here?
ناكاميتشي؟ كنت لا تزال في النُزل؟
Yeah. I had worked up a sweat playing ping-pong
أجل، تعرّقتُ كثيراً بعد لعب كرة الطاولة
so I took a quick dip in the public bath.
فاستحممت في الحمام العام
I felt bad for making you and Omura go on ahead and save our spot,
أنّبني ضميري لتركك وأومورا تذهبان قبلنا لحجز موقع
but you two were taking a bath too, correct?
لكنّكما كنتما تستحمان أيضاً، صحيح؟
Yeah. We were in the open-air bath, though...
أجل، لكنّنا كنا في الحمام المفتوح
If only we had gone to wake her up, she might still be--
...لو ذهبنا لإيقاظها آنذاك، لربما
What are you talking about?
ما الذي تقولينه؟
Yumi died while we were playin' ping-pong!
ماتت يومي بينما كنّا نلعب كرة الطاولة
We would've been too late no matter what...
لم نكن لنصل في الوقت بأيّ حال
Say. Can I ask you something?
أيمكنني سؤالك عن شيء؟
Alright, Omura.
حسناً يا أومورا
You're hiding something, aren't you?
أنت تخفي شيئاً، صحيح؟
You've been acting strange since this evening!
كنتَ تتصرف بغرابة هذا المساء
Come clean! What're you hiding?!
!اعترف! ما الذي تخفيه؟
Nothing!
...لا شيء
Don't tell me you did this?!
...أيمكن أنّك
I saw her!
!لقد رأيت
When I left to go to the bathroom!
!عندما ذهبت لدورة المياه
You saw the killer?!
رأيت القاتل؟
No! I saw Yumi!
كلا، رأيتُ يومي
What are you talking about?!
ما الذي تتكلم عنه؟
It was after 5:00 when you went to the bathroom!
ذهبت لدورة المياه بعد الخامسة
Yumi was already dead by then!
كانت يوري ميتةً في ذاك الوقت
That's just it!
صحيح
I saw her even though she was dead!
!رأيتُها بينما يُفترض أنها ميتة
She was glaring at the ping-pong room from an upstairs window!
كانت تحدّق بنظرات مخيفة نحو غرفة كرة الطاولة !من نافذة الطابق العلوي
That can't be! Yumi was already dead!
...لا يمكن! كيف ويُفترض أنها ماتت
Don't be stupid! That's impossible!
!لا تكن أحمق! هذا مستحيل
What if what I actually saw was her... her...
...ماذا لو ما رأيته كان... كان
Get serious! There's no such thing as ghosts!
!ارجع لصوابك! لا وجود للأشباح
Your mind was just confused because you were tired!
كان دماغك مشوّشاً من الإرهاق فقط
You were just imagining things!
لذا كنتَ تتخيّل أشياء كتلك
Yeah, maybe...
...ر-ربما
Did something happen at our inn?
أحصل شيءٌ ما في نُزلنا؟
What's all this about ghosts and dying?
ما هذا الكلام عن الأشباح والموت؟
My friend was shot.
أُرديت صديقتنا بالنار
Then they need medical treatment right away!
!علينا علاجها فوراً إذاً
It's too late for that.
فات الأوان
The police are on their way as we speak.
الشرطة في طريقها بينما نتكلم
Wait a minute! That's strange!
لحظة، هذا غريب
Why did that person say that at that time?!
لمَ قال الشخص هذا في ذاك الوقت؟
Don't tell me the murderer is one of you?!
أيمكن أنّ المجرم بينكم؟
Of course not!
!بالطبع لا
The murderer was someone else! Don't worry!
كان المجرم شخصاً من الخارج! لا حاجة للقلق
Wait! Where are you--
!انتظر
Nakamichi! You're in charge!
ناكاميتشي، أترك الباقي لك
I gotta use the restroom!
سأذهب لدورة المياه
Hey! Mori!
!أنت، موري
Say, isn't it too early to tell that this was an outside job?
أليس الجزم بأنّها جريمة خارجية أمراً مبكراً يا عمّ؟
After all, the way Yumi-san was killed was--
...فالطريقة التي قُتلت فيها يومي-سان
Hey, are you even listening?
أتسمعني يا عمّ؟
Quiet! I don't need any of your babbling!
!اخرس! لا أحتاج ثرثرتك
This was no outside job!
لم تكن جريمة خارجية
Would someone who snuck in from outside
هل يُقدم شخص تسلّل من الخارج
kill somebody and make it look like a suicide?!
على قتل أحدهم ثمّ تكبّد جعله انتحاراً؟
This was an inside job!
!كان المجرم من الداخل
In other words, it was one of my best friends!
!أي أحد أصدقائي المقرّبين
I don't know why or how they did it,
لا أعرف دافعه أو أيّ حيلة استعمل
but I won't let them get away with this!
!لكنّه لن يفلت أبداً
I'll expose them for what they are! This I swear!
!سأسحبه للعلن بالتأكيد! أقسم بذلك
Old man...
...عمّ
He's right.
معه حقّ
One of those four is the murderer.
المجرم أحد أولئك الأربعة
No, I have a good idea who it is.
كلا، لديّ فكرة عمّن يكون
It's most likely the person who said that one odd thing.
إنّه ذاك الذي تفوّه بالكلام الغريب آنذاك
But that person has a perfect alibi--
لكنه يملك حجّة غياب قويّة
they were in the ping-pong room with everyone else!
فقد كان في غرفة كرة الطاولة مع الجميع
I checked Yumi-san's estimated time of death for myself,
تحققتُ من زمن وفاة يومي-سان بنفسي
so that can't be wrong.
فلا خطأ فيه
In which case, how did that person kill her?
إذاً كيف فعلها ذاك الشخص؟
What bothers me
ما يضايقني
is the fact that Yumi-san's finger wasn't on the trigger
هو عدم وجود إصبع يومي-سان على زناد المسدّس
of the gun placed in her hand.
الذي كان في يدها
You would expect the killer to put her finger on it
...يُفترض أنّ القاتل سيضعه عادةً
to fake her suicide...
لتزييف الانتحار
It also bothers me that she didn't have any undergarments on
كما يحيّرني عدم وجود ملابس داخلية عليها
and that she had changed into a large yukata...
وتغيير ثوبها ليوكاتا كبير المقاس
Did the killer change her clothes?!
أيمكن أنّ القاتل بدّل ثوبها؟
What for?
لمَ؟
Benkei...
...بينكي
Come to think of it, that's the name of this inn, too...
...اسم هذا النُزل بينكي أيضاً
The fact all these arrows are stuck in him
وجود كلّ هذه الأسهم عليه
must mean this is from when Benkei died standing up.
يعني أنّه تمثال موت بينكي واقفاً
Died standing up?
موته واقفاً؟
That's it! Benkei!
!هكذا إذاً! بينكي
The killer used this!
!استعمل القاتل هذا
I've finally figured out the trick the killer used!
!اكتشفتُ الحيلة التي استعملها القاتل أخيراً
Here goes!
حسنٌ
I'll just put the old man to sleep like always
...سأنوّم العمّ بمسدّس ساعة التخدير كالعادة
This was an inside job!
!كان المجرم من الداخل
In other words, it was one of my best friends!
!أي أحد أصدقائي المقرّبين
I won't let them get away with this!
!لكنّه لن يفلت أبداً
I'll expose them for what they are! This I swear!
!سأسحبه للعلن بالتأكيد! أقسم بذلك
Understood, old man.
أفهم يا عمّ
But why did the killer shoot her?
لكن لمَ أطلق القاتل عليها؟
Perhaps the killer came to steal her things
لعلّه أتى لسرقة أمتعتها
but shot her when she spotted him.
لكنّه أطلق عليها عندما رأته
But isn't it strange?
لكن أليس ذلك غريباً؟
Why didn't we hear the shot when we were playing ping-pong?
لمَ لم نسمع صوت الطلقة عندما كنّا نلعب كرة الطاولة؟
Why?
لمَ؟
The killer has to be in here, so why do they all have alibis?!
يُفترض أنّ القاتل هنا، فلمَ يملكون جميعهم حجّة غياب؟
Judging from the state of her rigor mortis,
،بناءً على حالة تصلّب جثّتها
Yumi's estimated time of death was around 3:00 p.m.
فزمن وفاة يومي المقدّر كان عند قرابة الثالثة مساءً
Which means she was murdered immediately after she left us
مما يعني أنّ يومي قُتلت فورما تركتنا
and returned to her room.
وذهبت لغرفتها
The rest of us were in the ping-pong room from 3:00 to 6:00.
كان بقيّتنا في غرفة كرة الطاولة من الثالثة حتّى السادسة
Nobody had the chance to kill her.
لم يمتلك أحد فرصة لقتلها
What bothers me is what Omura said...
...ما يحّيرني هو ما قاله أومورا
That's just it!
صحيح
I saw her even though she was dead!
!رأيتُها بينما يُفترض أنها ميتة
She was glaring at the ping-pong room from an upstairs window!
كانت تحدّق بنظرات مخيفة نحو غرفة كرة الطاولة !من نافذة الطابق العلوي
Omura went to the bathroom just after 5:00.
ذهب أومورا لدورة المياه بعد الخامسة
Yumi couldn't have been alive.
يستحيل أنّ يومي كانت حيّة
So why did Omura say that?
فكيف قال أومورا ذاك إذاً؟
Say...
...يا عمّ
Let's play ping-pong! Come on!
!لنلعب كرة الطاولة! هيّا
Hey!
...أنت
Conan-kun! What are you saying at a time like this?!
كونان-كن! ما الذي تقوله في وقتٍ كهذا؟
My shakehand grip is pretty good, you know!
!مسكة المصافحة خاصتي ممتازة
That reminds me, Yumi-san used the shakehand grip too, huh?
تذكرت، كانت يومي-سان تستعمل مسكة المصافحة أيضاً، صحيح؟
Yeah, but you can't play right now! Okay?
أجل... لكن لا يمكنك اللعب الآن! فهمت؟
You're right.
سيكون عليّ تغيير ثيابي إن تعرّقت
Shakehand grip?
مسكة مصافحة؟
Come to think of it, Yumi had changed into a large yukata...
...أجل، بدّلت يومي اليوكاتا خاصتها لمقاسٍ أكبر
And had nothing on underneath!
ولم تكن ترتدي ملابس داخلية
And her right index finger stuck out stiffly
كما امتد إصبع سبّابتها الأيمن متصلّباً
instead of being on the trigger!
بدل أن يكون على الزناد
With the shakehand grip,
في مسكة المصافحة
you hold the racket with your index finger out.
تمسك بالمضرب وسبّابتك عليه
Could Yumi have been playing ping-pong with the murderer
أيمكن أنّ يومي كانت تلعب كرة الطاولة
before she was killed?!
مع القاتل قبل أن يقتلها؟
That's ridiculous. What purpose would that serve?
مستحيل، ما المعنى في ذلك؟
Wait a minute!
لحظة
I could swear they mentioned something at the police academy--
...قالوا سابقاً في أكاديمية الشرطة
Say, didn't Benkei die while standing up?
أخبريني يا جدّة، مات بينكي وهو واقف، صحيح؟
That's right.
أجل
Benkei fought hordes of enemies off all by himself
قاتل بينكي أفواجاً من الأعداء بمفرده
and then died on his feet when they showered him with arrows!
ثمّ مات واقفاً ووابل الأسهم يتساقط عليه
Oh! That's it!
!هـ-هكذا إذاً! فهمت
Hey, Mori. What's the shouting about?
موري، لمَ تصرخ؟
I've finally figured out who killed Yumi!
اكتشفتُ قاتل يومي أخيراً
What?!
!ماذا؟
Who is it, Dad?!
مـ-من هو يا أبي؟
You were the one who killed Yumi!
!قاتل يومي كان أنت
What? Nakamichi killed her?!
!ماذا؟ قتلها ناكاميتشي؟
Hey, stop joking around...
...يكفي مزاحاً
I was in the ping-pong room with everyone else
كنتُ في غرفة كرة الطاولة مع الجميع
at her estimated time of death!
أثناء زمن وفاتها المقدّر
Yes, your alibi is perfect.
أجل، حجّة غيابك متقنة
Assuming she really was killed at 3:00 p.m.!
بافتراض أنّها قُتلت في الثالثة حقاً
What are you talking about? We checked her time of death together!
ما-ما الذي تقوله؟ تحققنا من زمن الوفاة معاً
Yumi's toes were indeed beginning to stiffen,
كانت أصابع أقدام يومي قد بدأت بالتصلّب فعلاً
so I estimated that she had died over seven hours prior.
لذا قدّرتُ أنها ماتت قبل ما يفوق السبع ساعات
But there are exceptions:
لكن توجد استثناءات
sudden deaths during intense physical exertion.
كموت مُباغت أثناء نشاط بدني مُضنٍ
In such situations, intramuscular proteins harden more easily,
في تلك الحالات، تتصلّب بروتينات العضلات بيسر
causing rigor mortis to take effect much more quickly.
مما يسرّع تصلّب الجثّة
Yes. Just like the heroic Musashibo Benkei!
!أجل، كما مع البطل موساشيبو بينكي
So Benkei's death while standing up--
...موت بينكي وهو واقف إذاً
Yes. It's been medically proven
أجل، أُثبت طبياً
that it's possible to die while standing up.
أنّ الموت واقفاً ممكن
Come on, now. The body was in Yumi's own room!
بحقّك، كانت جثّة يومي في غرفتها
What kind of exercise are you saying I made her do?
أيّ نشاط بدني جعلتها تمارسه؟
No, she wasn't forced to exert herself in her room--
كلا، لم تُجبر على بذل جهد بدنيّ في غرفتها
it was in the ping-pong room!
!بل في غرفة كرة الطاولة
You made her play ping-pong right up until you killed her!
!جعلتها تلعب كرة الطاولة حتّى قتلتها
You were most likely supposed to meet her all alone
كان يُفترض أن تلتقي بها بمفردك
in the ping-pong room.
في غرفة كرة الطاولة غالباً
But then you invited us all into the room!
!لكنّك دعوتنا جميعاً للغرفة
Oh yeah! What do you say we play some ping-pong now?
وجدتُها، لمَ لا نلعب كرة طاولة الآن جميعاً؟
Sounds great!
!فكرة حسنة
I'll pass.
سأمتنع
Naturally, Yumi grew angry and returned to her room.
غضبت يومي بالطبع ورجعت لغرفتها
After 6:00, when everyone had left,
بعد السادسة كان الجميع قد غادروا
Yumi went by herself to the ping-pong room, where you were waiting.
وذهبت يومي لغرفة كرة الطاولة بمفردها حيث كنت تنتظر
It must've been quite the secret rendezvous.
لا بدّ أنّه كان لقاءً بغاية السرّية
You then invited her to a game of ping-pong.
دعوتها وقتها للعبة كرة طاولة
After making her exert herself for a while,
وبعد جعلها تبذل جهداً بدنياً لفترة
you got her to return to her room...
أرجعتها لغرفتها
...at which point you shot her in the head.
وأطلقت عليها النار في رأسها
All to skew the estimated time of death and create the perfect alibi!
كلّ ذلك للعبث بوقت الوفاة المقدّر وبناء حجّة الغياب المثالية
You likely used Yumi's short temper to your advantage
استعملت غالباً سرعة انفعال يومي لمصلحتك
to get her to return to her room.
لجعلها ترجع لغرفتها
As proof of this,
،ودليلاً على ذلك
Yumi rushed back to her room still holding the racket.
أسرعت يومي عائدةً للغرفة والمضرب في يدها
That's why her right hand which held the gun
لذا كانت يدها اليمنى التي تمسك بالمسدّس
had stiffened in the shakehand grip!
!متصلّبةً في مسكة مصافحة
So the Yumi I saw right after 5:00 was--
...يومي التي رأيتُها بعد الخامسة إذاً
Was the real Yumi, in the flesh.
كانت يومي الحقيقية
She was still alive then.
فقد كانت لا تزال حيّة
She was watching the ping-pong room
كانت تراقب غرفة كرة الطاولة
from the 2nd floor and waiting for Nakamichi to be all alone!
من الطابق الثاني وتنتظر خلوة ناكاميتشي
Yumi was probably really murdered at 6:30,
قُتلت يومي على الأرجح عند السادسة والنصف
when the fireworks show started!
مع انطلاق الألعاب النارية
The gunshot would seem inconspicuous with all the fireworks exploding about!
!فصوت الطلقة ستحجبه أصوات المفرقعات
But Nakamichi still had the job
لكن لا يزال أمام ناكاميتشي
of wiping off the body's sweat and changing the clothes--
مهمة مسح عرق الجثّة وتغيير ثيابها
there was a chance the trick could be discovered
كان هناك احتمال باكتشاف الحيلة
if we learned that she had been sweating.
إن عرفنا تعرّقها
He had no choice but to remove her undergarments,
لم يكن أمامه خيار سوى نزع ملابسها الداخلية
but he did change her yukata...
لكنّه غيّر اليوكاتا
...with a spare one.
بآخر بديل
But in the middle of his work, an unforeseen obstacle appeared:
لكن ظهرت عقبة غير متوقعة في منتصف عمله
Ran and Conan, who came to wake Yumi up.
فران وكونان كانا قد أتيا لإيقاظ يومي
You stopped your work halfway through,
أوقفت عملك غير مكتملاً
exited onto the roof through the window,
وخرجت للسقف من النافذة
and stopped Ran from entering the room.
ومنعت ران من دخول الغرفة
You then went with everyone to see the fireworks,
،ثمّ ذهبت رفقة الجميع للألعاب النارية
pretended to get separated,
،وتظاهرت بانفصالك
and finished the rest of your work.
لتذهب وتنهي بقيّة العمل
That's when you put the gun in her hand to make it look like a suicide.
عندها وضعت المسدّس في يدها لتجعله يبدو انتحاراً
Though it would seem that her hand
مع أنّ يدها كانت قد تصلّبت
had already stiffened into that peculiar grip,
بتلك المسكة سلفاً
making it impossible to put her finger on the trigger.
فاستحال وضع إصبعها على الزناد
Your theory is indeed interesting.
استنتاجك مُثير حقاً
But do you have any proof that I did it?
لكن ألديك أيّ دليل؟ دليل أنّي المجرم؟
Don't be a fool!
!لا تكن أحمق
The only person besides me who could've pulled that off
الوحيد الذي سيفكّر بحيلة كتلك
was you, a police detective!
!هو أنت أو أنا، الشرطّيين
See! You could've done it as well!
رأيت؟ كان يمكن أنّك الفاعل أيضاً
And besides, anybody could learn that from a book.
كما يمكن لأيّ حد الاطّلاع على تلك المعلومة في كتاب
Why, you!
!تـ-تبّاً لك
You sure are dumb, old man.
يا لسذاجتك يا عمّ
This great policeman couldn't possibly be the killer.
يستحيل أن يكون هذا الشرطيّ العظيم القاتل
Great policeman?
الشرطيّ العظيم؟
Don't you think?
ألا تتفق؟
He knew that Yumi-san was dead just by seeing her covered in blood!
فقد عرف أنّ يومي-سان ميتة بمجرد النظر لها في الدماء
You said the following without ever touching Yumi...
...قلتَ وقتها قبل لمس يومي حتّى
Yumi!
!يومي
Don't touch her!
!لا تلمسيها
Nobody but me and Mori are to come in here, since we're detectives!
!لا يدخل أحد هذه الغرفة سوى المحققين، أنا وموري
For some reason you called not for an ambulance,
،لسببٍ ما، لم تطلب الإسعاف
but for the police!
بل الشرطة
You knew that it was too late!
كنتَ تعرف أنّ الأوان قد فات
Because you killed her!
!لأنّك قتلتها
How could you?!
!كيف يمكنك؟! كيف يمكنك؟
Shut up!
!اخرس
I didn't want to kill her!
!لم أرد قتلها
We went out for eighteen years, you know!
!فقد تواعدنا لثمانية عشر عاماً
Eighteen years?!
ثمانية عشر عاماً؟
That's right!
!أجل
Until I met someone half a year ago!
حتّى التقيت فتاةً أخرى قبل نصف سنة
You did this because she would hinder your marriage?!
قـ-قتلتها لأنها ستعيق زواجك؟
Why? Why didn't you marry her?!
!لمَ؟! لمَ لم تتزوّجها؟
Let go!
!دعني
I proposed to her many times!
لطالما تقدّمتُ لها
But her answer was always no!
!لكن رفضها كان ثابتاً
For eighteen long years!
!لثمانية عشر عاماً
Just when I was about to marry someone else,
وعندما كنتُ على وشك الزواج بفتاة أخرى
Yumi told me this:
:أخبرتني يومي بالتالي
I won't allow it.
لن أسمح لك
I won't allow you to be happy.
لن أسمح لك بالسعادة
That's when her threatening letters and phone calls
وعندها أغرقتْ خطيبتي برسائل التهديد
to my fiancé started.
والمكالمات
Finally she said she was going to send photos of just the two of us!
قالت في النهاية أنّها سترسل صوراً !لنا نحن الاثنين معاً
I told her that if she brought the photos to the reunion
أخبرتُها إن أحضرتها كلّها للمّ الشمل
I would buy them all off of her.
فسأشتري الصور
That was the day you caught the bank robber.
كان ذلك في يوم قبضك على سارق البنك
I had just met with Yumi.
كنتُ قد التقيت يومي للتوّ
I was struggling over what to do about her...
...كنتُ حائراً فيما أفعل حيالها
...when the robber's gun fell nearby.
عندما طار مسدّس اللص بالقرب...
It was then that I thought up this plan.
خطرت لي الخطّة آنذاك
The deal was to take place in the ping-pong room,
كان يُفترض أن تتم الصفقة في غرفة كرة الطاولة
but then I told her this:
:لكنّي أخبرتها بالتالي
"The photos have been removed from your things."
"اختفت الصور من أمتعتك"
I see.
فهمت
So that's why Yumi rushed back to her room,
،لذا أسرعتْ للغرفة
racket still in hand!
والمضرب في يدها
And you followed behind and shot her!
ثمّ تبعتها وأطلقت عليها
That's right!
!صحيح
I shot the demon who screwed up my life!
!أطلقتُ على الشيطانة التي أفسدت حياتي
Which one was the demon?
أيّكما الشيطان؟
Shut up!
!اخرس
What the hell would you know?!
!ما الذي تعرفه؟! ماذا تعرف؟
I'll never know...
...لن أعرف أبداً
...how a murderer feels...
...شعور القاتل
...no matter what the reason!
مهما كان الدافع
I don't want to know!
لا أريد أن أعرف
Dad!
أ-أبي
Seems you're still as strong as ever...
لا تزال قويّاً كعادتك
Don't be stupid. You've just gotten weaker.
أحمق، أنت ضعفت فقط
Both your mind and your body.
في جسدك وعقلك
Yeah...
أجل
He's been pretty glum lately...
...إنّه مُحبط مؤخراً
You can't blame him; those were his friends...
ليس باليد حيلة، فقد كانوا أصدقاءً
That reminds me, if he's that strong,
،تذكرت، إن كان العمّ بتلك القوّة
why didn't he ever win any matches?
فلمَ لم يفز بأيّ مباريات؟
Apparently, in actual matches he gets so tense
يبدو أنّ الحماس يتملّكه وقت المبارايات
that he can't concentrate his strength.
فلا يستطيع تركيز قوّته
So he had a knack for being outdone...
كان ضعيفاً في المواجهات إذاً
I'll go try to cheer him up...
سأحاول إبهاجه في تلك الحالة
Wait.
انتظر
Let's leave him alone for a while.
لنتركه وحده لفترة
He'll be back to normal eventually.
سيعود لطبيعته في نهاية المطاف
This time it's pink!
!ورديّ هذه المرة
Oh, Inspector Megure! Good morning!
!مفتّش ميغوري! صباح الخير
Mr. Okida's dead?!
!مات الرئيس أوكيدا؟
It's damp!
بلل
For someone who died while sweating, there's too much here!
هذا عرقٌ كثيرٌ بالنسبة لشخصٍ مات بنوبة
If his heart attack was intentionally caused,
إن كانت نوبة الرئيس أوكيدا القلبية ،من تأثير شخص عمداً
then Tokito-san is the prime suspect!
فالمتّهم الأوّل هو توكيتو-سان
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Computer Murder Case.
جريمة قتل الحاسوب
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
"A cat."
قطّ